<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>ACM REP</title><link>https://acmrep.github.io/</link><atom:link href="https://acmrep.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>ACM REP</description><generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://acmrep.github.io/media/logo_hufd2b2b0046e49c7fbbb195201b371dcc_64552_300x300_fit_lanczos_3.png</url><title>ACM REP</title><link>https://acmrep.github.io/</link></image><item><title>Summary of ACM REP 2023</title><link>https://acmrep.github.io/post/20230714-acmrep23/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://acmrep.github.io/post/20230714-acmrep23/</guid><description>&lt;p>The inaugural &lt;a href="https://acm-rep.github.io/2023/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">ACM Conference on Reproducibility and Replicability&lt;/a> was held on 27-29 June 2023. The &lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/document/d/1FIeUcsjyf3JVr64sj8gWoDJrNc6C0467Q0VPKKj2Ux4" target="_blank" rel="noopener">program&lt;/a> included three keynotes and several sessions exploring topics in reproducibility and computer science, and a day of hands-on workshops. It was held at a wonderful space, the &lt;a href="https://cowellhaybarn.ucsc.edu/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Cowell Hay Barn&lt;/a> on the campus of the University of California, Santa Cruz. &lt;a href="https://dl.acm.org/doi/proceedings/10.1145/3589806" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Conference proceedings&lt;/a> are available from the ACM Digital Library.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The conference opened with introductory remarks by John MacMillan, Vice Chancellor of Research, UC Santa Cruz. MacMillan welcomed the participants and discussed the importance of open source software in reproducibility, mentioning the pioneering work of the &lt;a href="https://ospo.ucsc.edu" target="_blank" rel="noopener">UCSC Open Source Program Office (OSPO)&lt;/a>. The first keynote was delivered by Torsten Hoefler (ETH Zurich). Hoefler’s talk, &lt;a href="https://acm-rep.github.io/2023/author/torsten-hoefler/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Reproducing Performance - The Good, the Bad, and the Ugly&lt;/a>, gave an overview of the “reproducibility crisis” and noted that computer science as a discipline is doing quite well, with some areas better than others, for example machine learning. In the area of performance, Hoefler points out several issues that make reproducibility difficult to assess. Hoefler calls for a focus on interpretability and for the need to ensure that researchers in this area have a good grip on basic statistics to address known issues with speedup plots.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The second keynote of the day, &lt;a href="https://acm-rep.github.io/2023/author/juliana-freire/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Embracing Computational Reproducibility: Challenges, Solutions, and Cultivating Trust in Data-Driven Science&lt;/a>, was delivered by Juliana Freire (New York University). Freire discussed some of the challenges with current reproducibility tools and reminded us that reproducibility is not the ultimate goal, but rather trust in and explanation of the science. Enabling reproducibility allows others to assess whether a result is a discovery or a bug. She concluded with a call to action that includes better provenance capture and making computer science more like science. Two sessions, on advancing reproducibility and on testing reproducibility includes very interesting papers on cutting edge technologies and ideas related to reproducibility, including &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1145/3589806.3600032" target="_blank" rel="noopener">edge-to-cloud experiments&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://dl.acm.org/doi/10.1145/3589806.3600035" target="_blank" rel="noopener">reproducible execution of closed-source applications&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The second day began with a keynote from Grigori Fursin, co-chair of the MLCommons task force on automation and reproducibility, president of the cTuning foundation, and founder of cKnowledge.org titled, &lt;a href="https://acm-rep.github.io/2023/author/grigori-fursin/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Toward a common language to facilitate reproducible research and technology transfer: challenges and solutions&lt;/a>. Fursin described the work he’s been doing on reproducibility, which aims to provide portability by identifying the basic blocks that can be abstracted from all scripts. A panel session on &lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/document/d/12VjVeGxVT7prkK_UE2a8VDfhy-kapNO__5K5fRQosnU/edit?usp=sharing" target="_blank" rel="noopener">The Role of Open Source in Open Science&lt;/a> featured an impressive lineup of speakers including Sayeed Choudhury (Carnegie Mellon University), Stephanie Lieggi (UCSC), Zach Chandler (Stanford), and Malvika Sharan (Turing Project). Panelists spoke about their experience with open science and discussed whether reproducibility and replicability are technical or scientific issues. The fascinating and wide-ranging conversation also touched on the efforts and challenges to make open science more inclusive, and the still lingering, though diminishing, confusion about definitions of reproducibility, among other issues. Two other sessions, one in the morning and one in the afternoon, included fantastic papers on &lt;a href="https://dl.acm.org/doi/10.1145/3589806.3600041" target="_blank" rel="noopener">cost and benefits of reproducibility&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://dl.acm.org/doi/10.1145/3589806.3600033" target="_blank" rel="noopener">teaching reproducibility in the CS curriculum&lt;/a>, and on novel approaches to GPT &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1145/3589806.3600034" target="_blank" rel="noopener">benchmarks for reproducibility&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/document/d/1749zpWFdQSloxTWL3JaQjxKeKlswd74m9q0SfGqWsnk/edit#heading=h.mwm0idpj5i6q" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Three workshops&lt;/a> were offered on the last day of the conference. Checking Reproducibility with the Open Research Knowledge Graph, led by Hassan Hussein and Anna-Lena Lorenz (both of TIB - Leibniz Information Centre for Science and Technology), focused on the reproducibility assessment functionality of the Open Research Knowledge Graph (ORKG), a platform for structured semantic knowledge. Kate Keahey and Mark Powers (University of Chicago), led a Practical Reproducibility for Computer Science Hackathon, teaching participants how to package their computer science research experiments so they are “practically reproducible.” The afternoon workshop was taught by Reed Milewicz and Miranda Mundt (Sandia Labs) on the topic of Software Quality Practices for Reproducibility and included activities on the topic and techniques for incorporating practices that facilitate reproducibility in the software development process.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>About the &lt;a href="https://acmrep.github.io/">ACM REP&lt;/a>: The conference brings together a broad and inclusive intellectual community around the issues of reproducibility of computational research, including practical, actionable aspects of reproducibility in broad areas of computational science and data exploration, with special emphasis on issues in which community collaboration can be essential for adopting novel methodologies, techniques and frameworks aimed at addressing some of the challenges we face today. The ACM REP conference series is associated with the ACM Emerging Interest Group for Reproducibility and Replicability (see &lt;a href="https://acmrep.github.io/history">ACM REP’s history&lt;/a>).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The inaugural conference was a hybrid conference, organized by conference chairs Carlos Maltzahn (UC Santa Cruz) and Philippe Bonnet (IT University of Copenhagen), Tanu Malik (DePaul University) and Jay Lofstead (Sandia National Laboratories), Program Chairs. Thanks to local arrangement superstars, Stephanie Lieggi and Yelena Martynovskaya from UC Santa Cruz for the welcoming environment, thoughtful attention to detail, and delicious food.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The History of ACM REP</title><link>https://acmrep.github.io/history/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://acmrep.github.io/history/</guid><description>&lt;hr>
&lt;p>The ACM REP evolved from the International Workshop on Practical Reproducible Evaluation of Computer Systems (P-RECS) which was started by &lt;a href="https://ivotron.me/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Ivo Jimenez&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://people.ucsc.edu/carlosm" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Carlos Maltzahn&lt;/a>, and &lt;a href="http://lofstead.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Jay Lofstead&lt;/a> in &lt;a href="https://p-recs.github.io/2018/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">2018&lt;/a> in cooperation with ACM SIGHPC, co-located with the International Symposium on High-Performance Parallel and Distributed Computing (HPDC), and followed by four editions in &lt;a href="https://p-recs.github.io/2019/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">2019&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://p-recs.github.io/2020/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">2020&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://p-recs.github.io/2021/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">2021&lt;/a>, and &lt;a href="https://p-recs.github.io/2022/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">2022&lt;/a>, all co-located with HPDC. Since 2019 P-RECS was the annual forum for the &lt;a href="https://reproducibility.acm.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">ACM Emerging Interest Group for Reproducibility and Replicability&lt;/a> (EIGREP). In 2023 P-RECS merged into ACM REP as part of the effort of advancing EIGREP to a Special Interest Group (SIGREP).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://acmrep.github.io/admin/config.yml</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://acmrep.github.io/admin/config.yml</guid><description/></item><item><title>ACM REP Directory of Speakers</title><link>https://acmrep.github.io/directory/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://acmrep.github.io/directory/</guid><description>&lt;p>The ACM REP Directory of Speakers is intended as a resource for program committees of conferences, workshops, and similar gatherings for finding speakers who might be willing to talk about reproducibility.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Please &lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSdt998hKrXdjprK2KRggh3h2AF2Y1lAg_VwQqepJDkQOQITiw/viewform" target="_blank" rel="noopener">nominate&lt;/a> a person you want to have entered here. Nominations will be periodically reviewed by the ACM REP Steering Committee.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You can remove yourself from the list using &lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSc8db_2y58eBkFtdPMnyWTY0a3mYDcgv6mg9BsT4vCsj1HQAw/viewform?usp=sf_link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">this form&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="directory">Directory&lt;/h2>
&lt;table class="table">
&lt;tr> &lt;th>Name&lt;/th> &lt;th>Affiliation&lt;/th> &lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td data-table-dtype="text">Michael Heroux&lt;/td>
&lt;td data-table-dtype="text">Sandia National Labs&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td data-table-dtype="text">Lorena Barba&lt;/td>
&lt;td data-table-dtype="text">George Washington University&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td data-table-dtype="text">Michela Taufer&lt;/td>
&lt;td data-table-dtype="text">University of Tennessee, Knoxville&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td data-table-dtype="text">Todd Gamblin&lt;/td>
&lt;td data-table-dtype="text">Lawrence Livermore National Lab&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td data-table-dtype="text">Ivo Jimenez&lt;/td>
&lt;td data-table-dtype="text">Redpanda Data&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td data-table-dtype="text">Manish Parashar&lt;/td>
&lt;td data-table-dtype="text">University of Utah&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td data-table-dtype="text">Ian Foster&lt;/td>
&lt;td data-table-dtype="text">Argonne National Lab &amp;amp; University of Chicago&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;caption>Table: Speaker Directory&lt;/caption>
&lt;/table></description></item><item><title>Conferences with Reproducibility</title><link>https://acmrep.github.io/conferences/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://acmrep.github.io/conferences/</guid><description>&lt;p>The Conferences with Reproducibility is intended as a community-maintained resource that lists all computer science conferences that have an initiative related to reproducibility, especially awards recognizing reproducibility artifacts. The conferences are listed in this &lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1UsR0ZrL4OiQ-aVJSii2XzLybE-OYg5HOaPWTvhfAhd4/edit?usp=sharing" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Google Sheet&lt;/a> using a new tab for each calendar year.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="alert alert-note">
&lt;div>
&lt;p>If you find that a particular conference is not listed, please consider updating the &lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1UsR0ZrL4OiQ-aVJSii2XzLybE-OYg5HOaPWTvhfAhd4/edit?usp=sharing" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Google Sheet&lt;/a> (you should have write access).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Every recipient of the reproducibility awards is likely an example of practice that advances the state of the art of practical reproducibility. Please help making these examples known to the ACM REP community.&lt;/p>
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div></description></item><item><title>Diversity &amp; Inclusion</title><link>https://acmrep.github.io/diversity/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://acmrep.github.io/diversity/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>ACM REP is committed to Diversity, Equity, and Inclusion in Computing and Reproducibility.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Following &lt;a href="https://www.acm.org/diversity-inclusion/about" target="_blank" rel="noopener">the model set forth by the overall ACM community&lt;/a>, the ACM REP community encompasses the wide range and diverse set of professionals working on reproducibility and computing, from educators and researchers to software and hardware developers, system engineers, project managers, and data scientists.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As noted by the ACM, &amp;ldquo;Diversity is achieved when the individuals around the table are drawn from a variety of backgrounds and experience, leading to a breadth of viewpoints, reasoning, and approaches [&amp;hellip;] Equity is achieved by supporting the participation of marginalized communities in computing as well as by promoting impartiality and fairness within the procedures, processes, and distribution of resources and systems [&amp;hellip;] [and] Inclusion is achieved when the environment is characterized by behaviors that welcome and embrace diversity.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>ACM REP is committed to creating an environment that welcomes new ideas and perspectives, and where hostility or other antisocial behaviors are not tolerated. Conference organizers welcome participation and contribution from participants representing different ages, races, genders and sexual orientation, nationality, physical ability, thinking style and experiences to enhance the overall richness in providing quality programs and services for the global community. We also recognize the need to make services, activities, events, etc. more inclusive for individuals with disabilities. We are open to make accommodations and arrangements so that all those interested can participate fully in our events and activities.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Nominations</title><link>https://acmrep.github.io/nominations/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://acmrep.github.io/nominations/</guid><description>&lt;p>How do people get nominated to steering committee, become program chairs, etc.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>