<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>ACM REP</title><link>https://acmrep.github.io/</link><atom:link href="https://acmrep.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>ACM REP</description><generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><image><url>https://acmrep.github.io/media/logo_hufd2b2b0046e49c7fbbb195201b371dcc_64552_300x300_fit_lanczos_3.png</url><title>ACM REP</title><link>https://acmrep.github.io/</link></image><item><title>The History of ACM REP</title><link>https://acmrep.github.io/history/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://acmrep.github.io/history/</guid><description>&lt;hr>
&lt;p>The ACM REP evolved from the International Workshop on Practical Reproducible Evaluation of Computer Systems (P-RECS) which was started by &lt;a href="https://ivotron.me/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Ivo Jimenez&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://people.ucsc.edu/carlosm" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Carlos Maltzahn&lt;/a>, and &lt;a href="http://lofstead.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Jay Lofstead&lt;/a> in &lt;a href="https://p-recs.github.io/2018/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">2018&lt;/a> in cooperation with ACM SIGHPC, co-located with the International Symposium on High-Performance Parallel and Distributed Computing (HPDC), and followed by four editions in &lt;a href="https://p-recs.github.io/2019/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">2019&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://p-recs.github.io/2020/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">2020&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://p-recs.github.io/2021/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">2021&lt;/a>, and &lt;a href="https://p-recs.github.io/2022/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">2022&lt;/a>, all co-located with HPDC. Since 2019 P-RECS was the annual forum for the &lt;a href="https://reproducibility.acm.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">ACM Emerging Interest Group for Reproducibility and Replicability&lt;/a> (EIGREP). In 2023 P-RECS merged into ACM REP as part of the effort of advancing EIGREP to a Special Interest Group (SIGREP).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://acmrep.github.io/admin/config.yml</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://acmrep.github.io/admin/config.yml</guid><description/></item><item><title>ACM REP Directory of Speakers</title><link>https://acmrep.github.io/directory/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://acmrep.github.io/directory/</guid><description>&lt;p>The ACM REP Directory of Speakers is intended as a resource for program committees of conferences, workshops, and similar gatherings for finding speakers who might be willing to talk about reproducibility.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Please &lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSdt998hKrXdjprK2KRggh3h2AF2Y1lAg_VwQqepJDkQOQITiw/viewform" target="_blank" rel="noopener">nominate&lt;/a> a person you want to have entered here. Nominations will be periodically reviewed by the ACM REP Steering Committee.&lt;/p>
&lt;table class="table">
&lt;tr> &lt;th>Name&lt;/th> &lt;th>Affiliation&lt;/th> &lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td data-table-dtype="text">Michael Heroux&lt;/td>
&lt;td data-table-dtype="text">Sandia National Labs&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td data-table-dtype="text">Lorena Barba&lt;/td>
&lt;td data-table-dtype="text">George Washington University&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td data-table-dtype="text">Michela Taufer&lt;/td>
&lt;td data-table-dtype="text">University of Tennessee, Knoxville&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td data-table-dtype="text">Todd Gamblin&lt;/td>
&lt;td data-table-dtype="text">Lawrence Livermore National Lab&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td data-table-dtype="text">Ivo Jimenez&lt;/td>
&lt;td data-table-dtype="text">Redpanda Data&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td data-table-dtype="text">Manish Parashar&lt;/td>
&lt;td data-table-dtype="text">University of Utah&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td data-table-dtype="text">Ian Foster&lt;/td>
&lt;td data-table-dtype="text">Argonne National Lab &amp;amp; University of Chicago&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;caption>Table: Speaker Directory&lt;/caption>
&lt;/table></description></item><item><title>Conferences with Reproducibility</title><link>https://acmrep.github.io/conferences/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://acmrep.github.io/conferences/</guid><description>&lt;p>The Conferences with Reproducibility is intended as a community-maintained resource that lists all computer science conferences that have an initiative related to reproducibility, especially awards recognizing reproducibility artifacts. The conferences are listed in this &lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1UsR0ZrL4OiQ-aVJSii2XzLybE-OYg5HOaPWTvhfAhd4/edit?usp=sharing" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Google Sheet&lt;/a> using a new tab for each calendar year.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="alert alert-note">
&lt;div>
&lt;p>If you find that a particular conference is not listed, please consider updating the &lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1UsR0ZrL4OiQ-aVJSii2XzLybE-OYg5HOaPWTvhfAhd4/edit?usp=sharing" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Google Sheet&lt;/a> (you should have write access).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Every recipient of the reproducibility awards is likely an example of practice that advances the state of the art of practical reproducibility. Please help making these examples known to the ACM REP community.&lt;/p>
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div></description></item><item><title>Diversity &amp; Inclusion</title><link>https://acmrep.github.io/diversity/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://acmrep.github.io/diversity/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>ACM REP is committed to Diversity, Equity, and Inclusion in Computing and Reproducibility.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Following &lt;a href="https://www.acm.org/diversity-inclusion/about" target="_blank" rel="noopener">the model set forth by the overall ACM community&lt;/a>, the ACM REP community encompasses the wide range and diverse set of professionals working on reproducibility and computing, from educators and researchers to software and hardware developers, system engineers, project managers, and data scientists.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As noted by the ACM, &amp;ldquo;Diversity is achieved when the individuals around the table are drawn from a variety of backgrounds and experience, leading to a breadth of viewpoints, reasoning, and approaches [&amp;hellip;] Equity is achieved by supporting the participation of marginalized communities in computing as well as by promoting impartiality and fairness within the procedures, processes, and distribution of resources and systems [&amp;hellip;] [and] Inclusion is achieved when the environment is characterized by behaviors that welcome and embrace diversity.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>ACM REP is committed to creating an environment that welcomes new ideas and perspectives, and where hostility or other antisocial behaviors are not tolerated. Conference organizers welcome participation and contribution from participants representing different ages, races, genders and sexual orientation, nationality, physical ability, thinking style and experiences to enhance the overall richness in providing quality programs and services for the global community. We also recognize the need to make services, activities, events, etc. more inclusive for individuals with disabilities. We are open to make accommodations and arrangements so that all those interested can participate fully in our events and activities.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Nominations</title><link>https://acmrep.github.io/nominations/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://acmrep.github.io/nominations/</guid><description>&lt;p>How do people get nominated to steering committee, become program chairs, etc.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>